Unfortunately, we're not quite ready to be all smiley.
不幸的是 我们还不能高兴得太早
Sebastian tells me it's going to be a few years before I can get
Sebastian 告诉我 我还需要几年时间才能拥有一辆自己的无人驾驶汽车
my own self-driving car, but the bigger problem is we haven't yet talked about
但更大的问题是我们还没谈到
how to actually use the procedure.
即如何实际地使用这个函数
All we've done is make them; until we can actually use them
我们所做的一切只是写出函数 在我们能够实际地使用它们之前
we don't have a good reason to be really happy yet.
我们还不能高兴得太早
We're going to learn how to use them next, then we'll be back to being smiley.
下面我们会学习如何使用它们 然后我们就高枕无忧了
Now we are going to learn how to use a procedure.
现在我们将要学习如何使用一个函数
The way to use a procedure, we need the name of the procedure, followed by
要使用一个函数 我们需要函数名称
a left paren, followed by a list of inputs.
后面加上一个左括号 再加上一系列输入
There could be any number of inputs, but it has to match the number of inputs
输入的数量不是固定的 但是它必须匹配
the procedure expects.
该函数所预期的输入数量
These inputs are sometimes called "operands."
这些输入有时被称为操作对象
They are sometimes called "arguments."
它们有时又被称为参数
We're not going to argue about that.
我们不会在这个上面多作讨论
We're just going to call them inputs.
我们就叫它们输入
You have actually already done something quite similar to this.
其实你已经做过一些类似的事情了
Back in Unit 1, you learned about using "find" on "strings."
在第一单元中 你学了如何对于 “string”（字符串）使用 “find”（查找）的功能
With "find" you would pass in one or two inputs.
通过 “find” 你能够传入一个或两个输入
The first input was a "string."
第一个输入是个字符串
That was the string you are looking for, that's the first input
那正是你在查找的字符串
and the second input could be a number, the position where you start
那是第一个输入 第二个输入可能是个数字
looking for that string.
也就是你从何处开始查找那个字符串
We use "find" in many ways in Unit 1, as well as you used it
在第一单元 我们用不同的方法来使用 “find”
yourself in the homework for Unit 1.
你在第一单元的作业中也使用过了
"Find" is a little different from the procedures that you define yourself.
“Find” 与你自己定义的函数还有细微的差别
First of all, it's built in.
首先 它是内置的
The other thing that was different is that, instead of just having "find," we had
另外一个差别是 我们并非只有 “find”
another input that was really over here.
我们还有另外一个输入
We have the string that we were doing the "find" in.. let's say it was
我们有使用 “find” 功能的字符串（在变量 “page” 当中）
in the variable page, that's really another input to find.
那才是我们要查找的另一个输入
We'll talk in a later class about why that's done differently, but it's
我们会在今后的课程中谈到为什么会有这些差别
very similar to calling a procedure where one of the inputs is over here
但这与调用函数很相似
the other two are here.
在此函数中 一个输入在那里 另外两个在这里
It's a little different from that and we won't get into that in this course but
两者间有细微的差别 我们在本课程中不会谈到这一点
in a later course you'll learn more about what this really means.
但在今后的课程中 你会学到其真正的意义
For all the procedures that you define yourself, we won't have any
对于所有你自己定义的函数
object to invoke them on.
我们不会调用它们
We'll just have the procedure to call and the arguments or operands or inputs
我们需要的只是有函数可供调用 以及有参数 或者操作对象或者输入
as you like to call them to pass in.
（不论你喜欢怎么称呼它们）可供传入
Let's see how that works with a simple procedure.
让我们用一个简单的函数来看一看它如何工作
I am going to define the procedure "rest_of_string," and we'll give it the
我将会定义 "rest_of_string" 这个函数
parameter "s," so that means it takes one input and we are going to use the
给它一个名为 “s” 的参数 这意味着该函数需要一个输入
name "s" to refer to the value of that input.
并且我们会用 “s” 这个名称来指代这个输入的值
We'll make it "return to string" from the first character to the end.
我们将会用从第一个字符到最后一个字符来让它返回字符串
We will use the "string" indexing operator "return s [1:]."
我们会用字符串索引操作符 "return s [1:]"
This will evaluate to the "string," with the first letter removed, so all "strings" from
这将是首字母被除去的字符串
position 1 until the end of the "string."
所以 所有得出的字符串从1这个位置一直到字符串结尾处连成一排
That's what we return.
这就是返回的结果
So, the output of "rest_of_string" is that new string that starts from
所以 "rest_of_string" 的输出
the second letter in the input "string."
是从输入的字符串的第二个字母开始的新字符串
Here's an example of how to use this procedure.
这里有个例子 显示如何使用这个函数
We could call it directly.
我们可以直接调用
We could say "print rest_of_string."
我们可以写 "print rest_of_string"
That's our procedure.
这就是我们的函数
Now we are going to have our paren and we are going to pass in an input.
现在我们将用括弧 并传入一个输入
There's one parameter to "rest_of_string," so we need one input
"rest_of_string" 有一个参数
to pass in and it should be a "string."
所以我们需要传入这个参数 且它应该是个字符串
We'll pass in the string 'audacity'.
我们会传入 audacity 这个字符串
What happens when we call a procedure like this, execution will jump
当我们调用这样一个函数时
into the body of the procedure.
其执行会跳转到函数的主体
We can think of what the interpreter is doing now.
我们能够想到现在解释函数在做什么
Instead of running the code here, the interpreter will move.
它不会运行这里的代码 而会移动
When we call a procedure, it will jump to run the code inside the procedure.
当我们调用一个函数时 它会跳转到函数内部运行代码
It will assign to the parameters the values passed in as the inputs.
它会给我们传入的输入赋值
We can think of this as there being an assignment that says now the value of
我们可以把它视作一个赋值
"s" is the value of this input that was passed in.
即现在 “s” 的值就是我们所传入的输入的值
Now we are going to evaluate the body of the procedure.
现在我们将执行函数的主体
In this case there's only one statement, it's this return statement.
在这种情况下 只有一个语句 就是返回语句
We are going to find this value, so s [1:].
我们将找到这个值 也就是 s [1:]
The result of that is going to be the string 'udacity'.
得出的结果将是字符串 udacity
Then we got to the return.
接着我们要返回
What return means is we're going to jump back.
返回的意思是我们会跳转
We're jumping back to where we called the procedure, but now we actually
跳转至我们调用函数的地方
have a result.
但是现在实际上我们已有了一个结果
When we jump back, the value that this evaluates to is whatever value we
当我们跳转时
returned.
得出的值正是我们所返回的值
In this case, it's the string 'udacity.'
在这种情况下 就是字符串 udacity
So we don't have our self driving car,
让我们在 Python 的解释器里尝试一下
but now you can define and use procedures.
我们将定义 "rest_of_string" 这个函数 使用 “s” 这个输入
This is a really powerful concept
我们会返回 s[1:]
Anything that we are going to do in the rest of the course and anything
我们在今后课程中所要做的任何事
almost anyone does in programming computers is all about defining
以及任何人在计算机编程中所做的事情都是关于
procedures and using procedures.
定义和使用函数
Now we should have a big smile.
现在我们可以高枕无忧了
We can think of our procedures in terms of mapping inputs to outputs.
我们可以将函数视作把输入映射到输出中
We can think of our humans as also mapping inputs to outputs.
我们也可以将人类视作把输入映射到输出中
We have inputs coming in through the eyes, through the
我们通过眼睛和嘴巴来输入
I won't try to draw any of the outputs of our human procedure, but since
我不会画任何人类函数的输出
quizzes now to check that you understand them well.
那么现在我们会有几个小测验 来检测你是否理解它们